Gurgen Verdian

39 Glenridge Avenue, Apt. 4 Montclair, NJ 07042

(973) 905-0828 gurgen.verdian@gmail.com

Profile

Experienced project manager and strategy consultant in the commercial (re)insurance brokerage space with a successful track record in programming, data visualization, automation, and data science. Leads the design and development process for global analytics applications.

Professional Experience

Aon plc – New York, New York Manager, Inpoint

March 2020 - Present

- Drive the adoption of best-in-class analytics and data visualization services within the Aon Inpoint group through Alteryx, Python, VBA and Power BI.
- Partner with engineering teams to design global client analytics tools based on stakeholder specifications.
- Streamline the process of ideation, design and automation of reporting documents to provide consistent deliverables to clients and colleagues.
- Increase the breadth and depth of carrier-client relationships by tracking business performance, identifying trends, uncovering new business opportunities and leveraging Aon's digital capabilities.
- Liaise with Inpoint's advisory teams to develop strategic plans for clients across a diverse range of industries.

Marsh LLC – New York, New York Vice President, Insurer Consulting Group

July 2014 – March 2020

- Developed and manage broker-insurer relationships through digital product enhancements, meaningful analytics and C-suite engagement in order to achieve maximum growth.
- Programmed visualization models tailored to the executive group which support critical decision-making and customer segmentation.
- Created Excel Add-In packages which have become a best-practice for the consulting group and increase
 efficiency and accuracy of our business intelligence tools.

MetLife - New York, New York

September 2011 - June 2014

Account Manager, Global Relationship Management

- Managed 14 global client accounts with a premium book value of \$500+ million and a product portfolio including Life, Dental and Auto & Home coverages.
- Developed best practices in pipeline management, internal reporting, market data analysis and client data reporting management.

Computer Skills:

- Python (pptx, pyxl, matplotlib, scipy)
- VBA
- SQL

- Power BI
- Alteryx

Education

Marymount Manhattan College, New York, NY

Bachelor of Science in Business Management, Marketing

Minor: Psychology

December 2010